appliancesonline.com.au 2017-04-25

# Privacy Policy - Appliances On

**Last updated:** 4 September 2015 

Winning Appliances Pty Ltd (ACN 002 193 688) and its related bodies corporate, including Appliances Online Pty Ltd (ABN 19 151 833 546); Big Brown Box Pty Ltd (ABN 96 152 553 145); Handy Crew Pty Limited (ABN 34 152 213 039), Best Home Chef Pty Ltd (ABN 66 159 385 841) and Powerbuys Australia Pty Ltd (ABN 97 160 033 483) (the **"Winning Group"** ) are committed to providing you with a high level of customer service. This includes protecting and maintaining the privacy, accuracy and security of the personal information you provide to us. We are bound by, and will abide by, the Australian Privacy Principles set forth in the Privacy Act (Cth) 1988. 

## About this Privacy Policy

The purpose of this Privacy Policy is to explain:

  * the scope and application of this Privacy Policy;
  * the kind of personal information the Winning Group may collect about you and how we collect the information;
  * how we use your personal information;
  * how we may disclose your personal information;
  * how we protect the information we hold about you; and
  * how you can access the information we hold about you.

This Privacy Policy applies to personal information collected by the Winning Group by any means or technology and whether we have asked for the information or not. By using the websites operated by the Winning Group, or otherwise interacting with us in relation to the products and services offered by us (including at our retail stores, trade shows or participating in competitions or promotions offered by us), you consent to the Winning Group using your personal information as set out in this Privacy Policy. 

### Links to other sites

Our websites may contain links to other sites that are not owned or controlled by the Winning Group. Please be aware that we are not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites and you access these sites at your own risk. We encourage you to be aware when you leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every website that you visit to identify how it collects and uses personal information.

## What kind of personal information do we collect and hold?

In the process of conducting our business, we are likely to collect a wide range of personal information about you. The type of personal information we collect generally includes your name, residential, shipping and billing addresses, email address, telephone or mobile numbers, as well as interests and information about your transactions with us or our business partners, including the products and services we provide to you. 

If you are accessing our products and services via our websites, we may use technology to collect information as to your activities, including the IP address of your computer (or other devices), your web browsing history on our websites and transactional data including your payment histories. 

We do not generally collect "sensitive information" (such as information about ethnic origin, religious or political views, health information etc) from you. 

If you are a participant of a competition organised by us, we may collect additional personal information from you. Please refer to the section "Competition Contestants" below for more information. 

### Credit card information

We do not store any credit card information obtained at our retail stores, by telephone or through our websites. We pass it onto our bank or where applicable, our supplier for processing. If you use PayPal to complete your transaction, your personal information (including credit card information) will be collected and used by PayPal in accordance with its privacy policy, which is available here: <https://www.paypal.com/au/webapps/mpp/ua/privacy-full>. 

We only retain the last 4 digits for verification of your credit card on delivery. In some instances we request a copy of your driver's licence and credit card to confirm delivery when you are not going to be at home or the products have been purchased as a gift to ensure the transaction is not fraudulent. This information is destroyed as soon as its accuracy is confirmed.

## How do we collect personal information?

The Winning Group collects personal information directly from you when you submit it online (including via email and live chats) to a website operated by the Winning Group, by telephone or facsimile, or in person at one of our stores or trade shows. 

There may also be occasions when we collect personal information from publicly available sources or third parties, such as via our business partners where we are responsible for delivering goods or services directly to you, or social media platforms such as Facebook or Twitter.

You have the option of not disclosing personal information to us or to use a pseudonym when dealing with us in relation to a particular matter, unless it is, in our view, impractical for us to deal with you that way or we are otherwise required by law or authorised by a court or tribunal to deal you on an identified basis.

### Cookies and web beacons

A cookie is a small text file that is stored on a user's computer for record-keeping purposes. We use cookies on the websites operated by the Winning Group. We use cookies to identify repeat customers and make it easier for you to navigate our site and where applicable, provide customer services to you (e.g. online live chats to assist with your purchase). If you reject cookies, you may still use our site, but your ability to use some features of our site will be limited.

Some of our business partners (e.g. tracking utility company) also use cookies and web beacons on our site. We have no access to or control over these tracking technologies. A tracking utility company uses cookies to analyse your navigation around our websites. This information is generally not personally identifiable, and is analysed to determine user preferences and provide feedback so we can make improvements to our websites. In limited cases they can assist visitors by notifying them of transactional issues.

### Information that you disclose publicly or via social media networks

The Winning Group provides contents and services on a range of platforms (including social media networks) with interactive features to which you may contribute. If you post your personal information in publicly accessible places or social media platforms, your personal information will become publicly available (subject to, where applicable, any privacy settings you have in place in social media platforms). The Winning Group will not be responsible for the protection of personal information you choose to publish this way. 

### How do we use personal information?

The Winning Group may use your personal information for the purposes for which it was initially collected or purposes related to such initial purpose if such purposes would be within your reasonable expectations. For example, to:

  * provide you with our products and services (including warranty services, repairs and replacement of products and customer care plan services);
  * respond to questions or product requests (including via online live chats);
  * forecast your future needs for our products and services;
  * keep a record of our dealings with each other and enable us to contact you when necessary;
  * develop a data profile to enable us to tailor our services to you; or
  * (where applicable) conduct competitions and promotions in which you participated.

We may also use your personal information for purposes authorised by laws or regulations, such as to prevent or investigate alleged crime or fraud.

### Direct marketing

In addition, in order to improve and better our offers and service, the Winning Group may, from time to time, use your personal information to contact you to identify promotions, competitions, products and services offered by us that may be of interest to you.

By supplying us your information, you give the Winning Group permission to communicate to you via email, SMS, MMS, social media and telephone to inform you about products and services offered by us or our business partners which are relevant to you. This permission is not limited in time unless you choose to opt out by contacting us using the contact information provided below, or by utilising an 'unsubscribe' facility on a communication we send to you in which case, the Winning Group will take steps to ensure you do not receive any such direct marketing information in future.

Some members of the Winning Group advertise with Google. Google may show you our advertisements based on your previous visits to our site. If you do not wish to see these advertisements you can opt-out by visiting the Google advertising opt-out page here: http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html

### Competition contestants

If you are a contestant of a competition held by us, subject to any "conditions of entry" to that competition and depending on the nature of the competition, we may require you to participate in photographs, videos or filming sessions, in which case, we will be in possession of your photographs, images or recordings of your voice. By participating in such competition, you consent to: 

  * the collection, release, publication or broadcasting of your personal information (including your name, photographs or video footages) as required by the relevant conditions of entry or by law;
  * disclosure of your personal information to sponsors of our competition; and
  * receiving marketing and promotional communications from us, our related entities and our sponsors from time to time via any medium.

## Disclosure of personal information

We never sell, rent, lease or disclose your personal information to other organisations, except as outlined in this Privacy Policy. Personal information provided to a member of the Winning Group may be shared with the Winning Group. In addition, we may disclose your personal information to organisations outside the Winning Group which assists us to deliver our products and services. These third parties are too numerous to list and they may change from time to time. Some examples of the types of such organisations include: 

  * our products and services suppliers, such as for supplying products ordered by you and providing services in relation to maintenance and repairs of products; 
  * financial services providers, such as our banks or third party supplier for securing payment of the products or services we provided to you, such as PayPal, and where applicable credit report agencies or debt collectors;
  * our extended warranty partner, who may wish to contact you to offer warranty services in relation to the appliance that you have purchased;
  * technology service providers, such as internet service providers, database management services, digital mail providers who send communications on our behalf, live help service providers and service providers for the prevention of fraud and protection of data;
  * service providers who performs market research or manage or review the services provided to you, such as Satmetrix or BazaarVoice; 
  * mailing systems and courier companies which organise delivery of the products you have purchased; and
  * our professional advisers, accountants, lawyers and auditors. 

These third parties may be located in Australia or overseas, including but not limited to the United States, the United Kingdom, the Netherlands and India. 

We require these organisations to maintain the confidentiality of your personal information and also seek to ensure that they adhere to the Australian Privacy Principles. These service providers are not permitted to use your personal information for their own marketing purposes. 

In addition, we may release your personal information under the following circumstances:

  * when required to do so by a court or under applicable laws or regulation (for example, a subpoena) or where requested by a government agency; 
  * where we consider a company or an individual may be engaged in fraudulent activity or other deceptive practices that a governmental agency should be made aware of; and 
  * to appropriate persons, where your communication suggests possible harm to others. 

### Rate and review

If you provide a review or rating for a product available on one or more of our websites, you agree that we may publish part or all of your review or rating together with your first name and suburb.

## Security

The Winning Group takes reasonable steps to ensure that your personal information is protected from misuse, interference or loss and unauthorised access, modification or disclosure. We have systems and procedures in place to protect your privacy whenever we collect, store, and use or disclose personal information. We regularly upgrade these systems and review our procedures to ensure high standards of security are used to protect your personal information. As a condition of working for the Winning Group all our employees sign a confidentiality agreement. However, since no system is 100% secure or error free, we cannot guarantee that your personal information is totally protected, for example, from hackers or misuse. If you enter personal information on our website, you should exercise due care to safeguard any passwords, ID number, or other special access features associated with your use of our website. 

We will take reasonable steps to destroy or permanently de-identify personal information from our systems which is no longer required by us. 

## How to access and amend personal information

We strive to keep your personal information accurate, up-to-date and complete. Our Privacy Policy enables you to find out what information we hold about you and correct that information if it is wrong.

If you become aware that any information we hold about you is incorrect or out-of-date, please let us know immediately. We will be happy to accept updated personal information in writing from the owner of that information at any time. However, in order to protect your privacy and security, we will take reasonable steps to verify your identity before granting you access or enabling you to make corrections of your personal information. Depending on the nature of your request, we may ask the owner of the information to complete a personal information request form.

Our objective is to respond to any request within a reasonable timeframe and no later than 30 days. We will inform you if this timeframe is not achievable.

In some circumstances, the Winning Group may not be in a position to grant access to personal information, such circumstances include:

  * providing access is likely to pose a serious threat to the safety of an individual or publicly;
  * providing access is likely to unreasonably impact on the privacy of others;
  * the request for access is frivolous or vexatious;
  * providing access would reveal information which relates to existing or anticipating legal proceedings or otherwise impact on any negotiations;
  * providing access is unlawful (including being unlawful as directed by a court or tribunal order) or is likely to impact on actions being taken in relation to alleged unlawful activities relating to the functions and activities of the Winning Group; or
  * granting access would impact on a commercially sensitive decision making process.

## Changes in this privacy policy

We reserve the right to modify this privacy policy at any time, so please review it frequently. Changes to this privacy policy will be published by posting an updated privacy policy on websites operated by the Winning Group. If we make material changes to this policy, we will notify you here, by email, or by means of a notice on our home page.

## Contact us

We encourage and value your feedback. If you have any questions about our Privacy Policy, or have a problem or complaint, please let us know. We will respond to a complaint as soon as possible, but within 10 working days to let you know who is responsible for managing your complaint. We will also try to resolve the complaint within 10 working days. When this is not possible, we will contact you within that time to let you know how long it will take to resolve the complaint.

Our contact details are:

**Winning Appliances Pty Ltd**  
PO Box 694, Strawberry Hills NSW 2012  
Attention: Privacy Officer 

Phone: 1300 050 050

E-mail: [privacy@winning.com.au](mailto:privacy@winning.com.au)

If you believe the Winning Group has not adequately dealt with your complaint, you may complain to the Privacy Commissioner, whose contact details are found on their website <http://www.oaic.gov.au/>.
